Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
- Benjamin Franklin Account Books, 1730-1874; Mss.B.F85.f6.numeral; 33 volumes
  - Account book, 1782; 1 vol. (on floor C); Franklin Benjamin
    This list is arranged by date of receipt and the entries are arranged by the line on the page (ther are 12 numbered double pages); number; where drawn; date drawn; term; tenor; in whose favor; dollars; livres; by whom drawn; by whom countersigned; check letters; whan accepted; and by whom presented. Most of these bills were drawn by Francis Hopkinson and John Adams. This volume was kept by the Franklins when in France.
  - Account book, 1782; 1 vol. (on floor C); Franklin Benjamin
    Ledger containing a list of loan office bills. This list is arranged by date of receipt and the entries are arranged by the line on the cage (there are 67 numbered double pages); number; where drawn; date drawn; term; tenor; in whose favor; dollars; livres; by whom drawn; by whom countersigned; check letters; when accepted; and by whom presented. Most of these bills were drawn by Michael Hillegas and Francis Hopkinson. This ledger was kept by the Franklins when in France.
  - Wastebook, 1785-1787; 1 vol.; Franklin Benjamin
    This volume was kept by Benjamin Franklin and there is a small notice, in his hand, pasted to a page: "B.F.s Private Acc[oun]ts." It consists of 18 pages recording payment of taxes, purchase of stockings, hats, bookcases, thermometer, hams, etc., servants wages, etc. Franklin's French expenses are on the first two pages under dates of December 1776-April 1777. At the end of the volume is an index and several pages of accounts with the Congress, William Temple Franklin, Caffieri, etc.
  - Receipt book of Sarah Read (Franklin?s mother-in-law), 1714-1746; 1 vol.; Franklin Benjamin
    The book of ca. 25 pages contains the occasional receipts written and signed in different hands, acknowledging receipt of funds from Mrs. Read. Benjamin Franklin signed one such receipt.
  - Ledger book of Peter Franklin, 1743-1762; 1 vol.; Franklin Benjamin
    This volume consists of 137 numbered double pages (debit and credit sides) of sales from 1741 to 1761. Peter Franklin entered sales from a general store, with certain extraordinary items sold: fish, beeswax, onions, "Delph" plates, black beads, fans, shoe buckles, fabrics, tea, nails, wood, planks, etc., to different people, among whom are names such as Governor Ward, John Banister, John Mecom, Sarah Gould "of the Vinyard," Ephraim Brown, John Franklin, etc.
  - Account book, 1786; 1 vol.; Franklin William Temple
    "Advances, on Account of the Sum Stipulated to be furnish'd, in his Agreement with Mr. W[illia]m. Pyne;" February 27-November 16, 1786. This vellum bound volume of ca.100 leaves, of which 8 contain writing, consists of the account of the tenant who farmed W.T.Franklin's "Farm in the Jersies," listing payments to Pyne and payments made by Franklin for ploughing;, seeds, horse, smith work, farming implements, etc.
  - Account book, family, 1786; 1 vol.; Franklin Benjamin
    "William T. Franklin's Advances for the Family. - being on Account of the Sum stipulated to be furnish'd in his Agreement with Mr. Pyne;" March 23, l786-Nov. 27, 1786. This vellum bound volume of ca.100 leaves, of which 10 contain; writing, consists of entries of barrel of pork; killing a calf; candles; soap; mustard; china; coffee pot; tea kettle; buckets; cheese; salt; etc., for use on W.T.Franklin's farm by the tenant family.
  - Post office book, letters received, 1767-1768; 1 vol.; Franklin Benjamin
    These printed forms were filled in in manuscript and list the letters received from other colonial post offices or from ships in the Philadelphia Post Office by Postmaster Thomas Foxcroft.
    The Papers of Benjamin Franklin, volume XIV, l47-148.
  - Post office book, letters received, 1764-1767; 1 vol.; Franklin Benjamin
    This is not, strictly speaking, a volume of accounts. It consists of a series of loose printed sheets, filled in in manuscript, under the headings of: Date of the Bills sent; To what Office the Letters were sent; Number of unpaid Letters, Single, Double, Treble, Pacquet, Sums unpaid, Dwt., Gr.; Number of paid Letters [broken down as the unpaid letters above]; Free Letters, Single, Double, Treble, Pacquet.
- Bejamin Franklin Estate Records, 1788-1797; Mss.B.F85.h; 31 items
  Two account books kept by Henry Hill (1732-1798), one of Franklin's executors and miscellaneous related material. Included are copies of Franklin's will, an inventory of the estate (copy), letters relating to claims on the estate, and recordings of receipts and disbursements made. The miscellaneous items include an interesting account with Robert Bass, Franklin's druggist, and a listing of medicine and surgery books belonging to Franklin.
  - Bound Volume 1: Letterbook, 1788 July 17-1798 Jan. 28; Franklin Benjamin
    Includes copy of will and codicils, an estate inventory, correspondence relating to decedents, information on heirs, and some accounts.
    - Franklin Estate Inventory
  - Bound Volume 2: Receipt book, 1790 April 29-1791 December 23; Franklin, Benjamin
    Records expenditures by Henry Hill and other executors on behalf of the Franklin estate
  - Extract of minutes, 1790 July 13; Pennsylvania Hospital (Folder 1)
  - to Nathan Jones, 1798 January 28; Hill, Henry, 1732-1798 (Folder 1)
  - to Executors of B. Franklin, 1791 July 10; Rogers, John (Folder 1)
  - List of Bonds, etc., of B. Franklin by Richard Bache, 1790 May 12 (Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benjamin Franklin with Thomas Seddon, et.al, 1790 April 29-1791 June 11 (Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benjamin Franklin with Thomas Seddon, et.al, 1790 April 29-1791 Dec. 23 (Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benjamin Franklin with Thomas Seddon, et.al, 1790 April 29-[1792] May 15 (Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benjamin Franklin with E. Mecom, 1791 June 29 - Dec. 23 (Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benjamin Franklin. Statement, 1790 May-1791 Sept. 15 (Folder 2)
  - Calculations for payment of 2,000, 1790 Oct. 18 (Folder 2)
  - Statement to Henry Hill, 1796 Sept. 18,22; Corkrin, James (Folder 2)
  - to H. Hill, n.d.; Hovey, Ebenezer (Folder 2)
  - Rects. Accts. of the Estate of Benjamin Franklin, 7p. (Folder 3)
    including title page
  - Certification that Henry Hill received sums for B. Franklin's account, 1791 Sept. 22; Febiger, Christian, 1746-1796 (Folder 3)
  - B. F. Bache account with Executors of the Estate of Benjamin Franklin, 1797 July 24-1793 August 4 (Folder 3)
  - Account with B.F.Bache, 1797 April 1-1793 February 4; Hill, Henry, 1732-1798 (Folder 3)
  - to Executors of the Estate of Benjamin Franklin, 1790 July 20; Miles, Samuel, 1740-1805 (Folder 3)
  - Affidavit.., 1791 April 30; Griffith, John, et al (Folder 3)
  - Extract from the Minutes, 1790 July 12; Philadelphia Common Council (Folder 3)
  - affidavit.., 1790 July 3; Greene, Elihu (Folder 3)
  - to Andrew Dexter, 1791 June 21; Carlile, John (Folder 3)
  - Account with Robert Bass, 1791 April 15; Estate of Benjamin Franklin (Folder 3)
  - to Benjamin Franklin Bache, 1797 April 8; Franklin, William Temple (Folder 4)
    Extract
  - to Henry Hill, 1790 Oct. 28; Franklin, William Temple (Folder 4)
    6pp. considered
  - Observations on letter of Jonathan Williams, 1790 Oct. 24; Franklin, William Temple (Folder 4)
  - to Jonathan Williams, 1790 Oct. 23; Franklin, William Temple (Folder 4)
    with J.Williams to W.T. Franklin 24 Oct.1790 on same leaf
  - Receipt for books and manuscripts, 1790 Oct. 28; Franklin, William Temple (Folder 4)
    Copy
  - Statement of Medical and Surgery books in B. F's Library, 1790 Nov. 2; Franklin, William Temple (Folder 4)
  - List of Medicine and Surgery books in Franklin's Library (Folder 4)
- Mme Brillon Collection, 1778-1788; Mss.B.F85.br; 19 items
  Biographical/Historical note
  A neighbor of Benjamin Franklin's when he lived at Passy, the French harpsichordist and composer Anne Louise Brillon became an intimate friend. Franklin attended the salon run by Mme Brillon and corresponded with her regularly when they were apart. Her best known composition, "Marche des Insurgents," celebrated the American victory over the British at Saratoga in 1777.
  Correspondence written by Benjamin Franklin to his French confidante, Anne Louise Boyvin d'Hardancourt Brillon de Jouy.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1778 March 10; AL, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    French translation, 3p. For copy in French, see Franklin Papers, vol.43, no. 19-1/2.
    Printed: Smyth, X, 437-438.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], [ca.1778] May 10; A.L. 2p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    See Franklin Papers, vol. 46, no.43; Smyth, X, 411f.
    Printed: Smyth, X, 412-414.
  - Letter to [Mme.d'Hardancourt Brillon], [ca.1778] July 27; A.L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    ----French translation in another's hand. 4p. For copy, see Franklin Papers, vol.46, no.47.
    Printed (in French): Smyth, X, 432-434
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], [ca.1778]; A.L. 2p. In French. 9x7 Enc. wanting.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    For copy, see Franklin Papers, vol.43, no.87 and 87-1/2.
    Printed: Smyth, X, 429-430.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], [ca. 1779? May]; A.L. 2p. In French. 8-1/2x6-1/2.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Accepts her proposal to become her father.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1780 July 10; A.L. 1p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Inquires after her health. Suggests exercise.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1780 Nov. 17; A.L. 2p. In French. Enc. wanting.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    For copy, see Franklin Papers, vol. 46, no.44, enc. wanting.
    Printed (with her corrections): Rosengarten, "Franklin's Bagatelles," A.P.S. Proceedings, vol.40, p.97.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1780 Nov. 23; A.L. 3p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Feminine intuition superior to reason.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1780 Nov. 29; A.L. 2p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Thanks her for correcting his French. Will bring her more of his writings.
  - Letter to [Mme. d' Hardancourt Brillon], 1780 Dec. 10 Sunday; A.L. 2p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Will visit her next week. Speaks of his illness.
    For copy, see Franklin Papers, vol. 46, no.42
  - Letter to [Mme. d' Hardancourt Brillon], 1781 Jan. 11; A.L. 1p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Reminds her that he never failed to visit her at least twice a week for four years.
  - Letter to [Mme. d' Hardancourt Brillon], 1781 Feb. 16; A.L. 1p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Van Doren, Benjamin Franklin, 644.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1781 Oct. 1; A.L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Worries about her journey and wishes he could carry her to Nice on wings. Mentions W. T. Franklin.
    For her answer, see Smyth, X, 424-25.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], [ca. 1781?] Oct. 12; A.L. 2p. "No.2."; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerning travel at his age and in his youth. Mentions LeRay de Chaumont. Mme. Veillard, Mme. Helvetius, and Abbé Morellet.
  - Letter to M. [and Mme.] Brillon, Nice, 1781 Oct. 30; A.L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Birth of the dauphin. His thoughts of her. Mentions W.T.Franklin.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], 1781 Dec. 12; A.L. 2p. "No.4." In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Hopes her trip is improving her health. Mentions Mme. Helvetius, comte d'Estaing. Speaks of great victory.
  - Letter to Mme. Brillon, Nice, 1782 Dec. 25; A.L. 3p."No.6." In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    For copy, see Franklin Papers, vol. 43, no.44-1/2.
    Printed: Smyth, VIII, 350-351.
  - Letter to [Mme. d'Hardancourt Brillon], [ca.1784] Saturday; A.L. 1p. In French. 8x6.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed (in English): Rosenbach, The All-Embracing Dr. Franklin, p.40.
  - Letter to Mme. Brillon, 1788 April 19; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    ----French translation in another's hand. 3p.
    Note in French.
    Printed in part: Smyth, IX, 643-645.
- Benjamin Franklin-Francis Childs Collection, 1783-1795; Mss.B.F85.ch; 19 items
  Francis Childs established himself as a printed with the assistance of Benjamin Franklin and became a pioneer in publishing daily newspapers in both Philadelphia and New York ( Daily Advertiser). Childs became the public printer in New York in 1790.
  Miscellaneous correspondence between Benjamin and William Temple Franklin and the newspaper publisher Francis Childs.
  - to F. Childs, 1783 May 11; Jay, John
  - to F. Childs, 1784 Dec. 20; Jay, John
  - to Francis Childs, 1785 April 22; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 Feb. 5; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 Feb. 25; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 March 26; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 April 22; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, [1786] 1785 May 1; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 June 4; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 June 18; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 June 28; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 July 27; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1786 Sept. 25; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1787 Jan. 15; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1788 Nov.19; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1789 April 27; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Francis Childs, 1790 Feb. 22; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to F. Childs, 1790 Oct. 25; Franklin, William Temple
  - to F. Childs, 1795 Jan. 11; Freneau, Peter
- Catherine Ray Greene Collection, 1751-1784; Mss.B.F85.g; 27 items
  A Rhode Islander, Catherine Ray Greene met Franklin in Boston in 1754 and remained a constant correspondent until his death. She became wife of William Greene, governor of Rhode Island from 1778-1786, with whom she had six children.
  Miscellaneous correspondence between Benjamin Franklin, his sister Jane Mecom, and their friend Catherine Ray Greene.
  - to Catharine Ray, 1751 June 7; de el Castillo, Laureano Donado
    In Spanish.
  - to Catherine Ray, 1751 June 7; de el Castillo, Laureano Donado
    English translation in B. Franklin's hand.
  - to Thomas Hubbart, 1751 n.d.; de el Castillo, Laureano Donado
  - to Katy [Ray], 1755 September 11; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Catherine Kay, 1755 October 16; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Katy Ray, [ca. 1755-1756]; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Catherine Ray, 1756 August 26; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Catharine] Greene, 1763 January 23; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Cath[arine] Greene, 1763 August 1; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Katharine Greene, [1763 November 10]; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Catherine Greene, 1764 February 15; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Cath[arine] Ray [Greene], 1778 February 28; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to William Greene, [1778] June 4; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Gov. [William] Green[e], 1783 May 20; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Catharine Green[e], 1764 June 14; Franklin, Sally
  - to [Catharine] Greene, 1775 November 24, December 2; Mecom, Jane
  - to W[illiam] Green[e], 1776 May 8; Mecom, Jane
  - to Catharine Greene, 1762 November 25; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - 1763 June 6
  - 1776 June 17
  - to [Catharine Greene], 1789 March 2; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1776 February 20, February 7; Greene, Catharine
  - to ---- ----, 1784 January 16; Greene, Catharine
  - to Jane Mecom, [1784?] February 12; Greene, Catharine
  - to Jane Mecom, 1776 June 21; Greene, Catharine
  - [1776?] March 12
  - [1784?] After August 22
- Benjamin Franklin-Richard Jackson Collection, 1753-1767; Mss.B.F85.j; 41 items
  A member of Parliament and colonial agent for Connecticut, Pennsylvania, and Massachusetts, Richard Jackson met Benjamin Franklin through their mutual friend Peter Collinson. The two shared a number of interests, including scientific interests in agriculture and natural history and politics. Jackson worked with Franklin in opposing the Stamp Act.
  Letters from Benjamin Franklin to Richard Jackson, and two letters from Samuel Finley, a minister and central figure in the Great Awakening.
  - to Richard Jackson, 1753 Dec. 6; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Richard] Jackson, 1754 Dec. 12; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1755 Oct. 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1762 Dec. 2; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1762 Dec. 6; ALS, 3p. Also copy of same L.S(?) 3p. and enc.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1763 March 8; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1763 April 11; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Rich[ar]d Jackson, 1763 April 17; ALS, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1763 June 6; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson; Woodbridge, N.J, 1763 June 10; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1763 June 27; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1763 Aug. 8; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1763 Sept. 22; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1763 Dec. 19; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Rich[ar]d Jackson, 1763 Dec. 24; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Argument for making the bills of credit bear interest, 1763 Dec.; D. 10p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1764 Jan. 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 Feb. 11; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 March 8; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 March 14; ALS, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Richard Jackson], 1764 March 29; ALS, 2p. and enc. - 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 March 31; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 May 1; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1764 June 1; ALS, 6p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1764 June 18; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 June 25; ALS, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1764 July 12; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 Aug. 9; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 Sept. 1; ALS, 7p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1764 sept. 20; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to R[ichard] Jackson, 1764 Sept. 25; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Richard Jackson, 1764 Oct. 11; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Rich[ar]d Jackson, 1764 Nov. 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Richard] Jackson; [London], 1767 Feb. 13; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Benjamin Franklin; Inner Temple, 1764 Aug. 11; Copy of L. 3p.; Jackson, Richard
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1762 Nov. 29; ALS, 1p.; Hughes, John
  - to [Benjamin] Franklin; Princeton, 1763 March 17; ALS, 1p.; Finley, Samuel
  - to [Benjamin Franklin]; Princeton, 1763 March 21; ALS, 1p. in B.F.'S hand.; Finley, Samuel
  - to B[enjamin] Franklin; Brunswick, N. Jersey, 1763 April; ALS, 3p.; Lyon, James
  - to Benj[ami]n Franklin; Lancashire Furnace, 1763 May 23; ALS, 2p.; Whick
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1763 June 23; ALS, 2p.; Hall, David, 1714-1772
- Jane Mecom Collection, 1728-1789; Mss.B.F85.m; 65 items
  The youngest and favorite sibling of Benjamin Franklin, Jane Mecom married the Boston saddler Edward Mecom in 1727. A constant correspondent of Franklin's, Mecom lived out the revolutionary years in Rhode Island (staying with Catherine Ray Greene) and Philadelphia (staying with Richard Bache), where she kept Franklin apprised of current events and public opinion on the course of the war. Mecom bore more than her share of hardships in life. Only nine of her eight sons and four daughters survived infancy, and two of them, including her son Benjamin, went insane in later life.
  Correspondence from Benjamin Franklin to his sister Jane Mecom written throughout his life.
  - to [Sister Davenport], ca. 1728-1730; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Sparks, Familiar letters...by B. Franklin, 1833, p.4.
  - to Jenny [Mecom], 1743 July 28; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.2,p.237.
  - to his father and mother [Josiah and Abiah Franklin], 1744 Sept. 6; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.2,p.281.
  - to his brother and sister [Edward and Jane Mecom], 1752 Sept. 14; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.3,p.101, under date of Nov. 14, 1752.
  - to Jane Mecom, 1756 June 10; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1756 June 28; ALS, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.3,333.
  - to his brother and sister [Edward and Jane Mecom], 1756 Dec. 30; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.3,356.
  - to Jane Mecom, 1757 April 19, 25; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.3,391.
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1758 Nov. 11; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1759 July 14; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1760 Jan. 9, March 26; ALS, 2p; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1762 Nov. 11; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1762 Nov. 25; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1763 Feb. 21; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1763 May 20; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1763 June 19; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1763 Nov. 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1763 Dec. 15; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1764 (?) July 24; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Jane Mecom, 1765 Aug. 29; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1766 March 1; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Sparks, v.7,443n.
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1767 Dec. 24; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1768 Feb. 21; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1768 Sept. 20; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [William Franklin; London], 1768 ?? October; L. 3p. Extract from letter.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1768 Nov. 20; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1769 Feb. 23; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Sparks, v.7, 437n.
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1769 April 27; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Smyth, v.5,206.
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1769 Sept. 29; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1771 July 17; ALS, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed in part: Sparks, v.7,380n.
  - to [Jane] Mecom, 1772 March 30; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1772 April 13; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to his sister [Jane Mecom], 1773 Oct. 9; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790